JOANN SUDIBYO -CV



JOANNSUDIBYO.COM

JOANNSUDIBYO@GMAIL.COM

EDUCATION

Australia Catholic University, Sydney, Australia Bachelor of IT (Information Technology) February 2015 – March 2018

University of London International Program, Singapore

Diploma of Economics August 2013 – July 2014

SKILLS

TECHNICAL

HTML & CSS SQL XML

Javascript Git

Tableau JIRA

PROFESSIONAL

Agile Scrum Communication

LANGUAGES

Bahasa Indonesia (native) English (fluent) Mandarin (beginner)

PROJECTS

www.whatsthesymbol.com

www.ptmjaya.com

REFERENCE

Will be provided upon request

PROFILE

Experienced and reliable Quality Analyst with over five years of experience in both manual and automated testing of Web, API and Mobile application in the education field to ensure the highest quality outcome possible.

Adapt in providing suggestions and solutions to improve and enhance productivity. Solid understanding of business requirements, software requirements specification and acceptance criteria.

Bringing forth a seasoned history of helping companies to achieve success and efficiency.

KEY SKILLS SUMMARY

- Agile & Scrum Methodologies
- Test Plans, Cases & Processes
- Regression & Negative Testing
 Negative Testing
- UI & API (SOAP/REST) Testing
- Cross-browser/Platform Testing
- End-to-end & Mobile-device Testing
- Defect & Bug Tracking
- Test Strategies & Coverages
- User Stories Creation & Documentation
- Automation & Manual Testing
- Sanity & Integration Testing

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Quality Analyst- 3PLEARNING, NORTH SYDNEY, AUSTRALIA (Full-Time) Jan 2018- present; (Casual) May 2015- Dec 2017

- Creating scenarios with test cases in web-based test management tool-I am responsible in creating multiple scenarios within the software to find full coverage of the products
- Experience in creating and documenting user stories, to alleviate my
 product manager's vision in expecting features to be created- I have
 experience in helping the business analyst and product owner to create
 user stories and communicate with the relevant stakeholders
- Working with mySQL database- I have experience in creating mock data for testing, creating queries to validate data and testing with large dataset
- Creating and executing automated tests with Postman in Javascript-I am responsible for developing and executing automated API testing of a software (other tools include WCF Client and Wizdler)
- Execute all levels of testing such as functional, regression and user acceptance testing- I practise this on a daily basis and have a strong knowledge in a product's life cycle
- Detect and track software defects and inconsistencies- I have experience in debugging issues during the testing phase in different environments
- Attlasian software knowledge in documenting business rules, acceptance criteria, bugs, tasks and improvements- I am responsible to record user stories in the confluence page and report any defects in Jira
- Experience in Agile Methodology and Scrum I am involved in daily stand up to keep track of assigned tasks and identify any impediments to ensure that we can complete our tasks efficiently and in a timely manner
- Use of company deployment tools I have experience in using the internal tools to deploy product content in different environments
- Ensure XMLs are in the correct format I have experience in decoupling the data of content to see and provide any errors